[{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of&nbsp; a if 2y - ax + 4 = 0 is perpendicular to the line y + <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4x<\/sub> - 7 = 0.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-4","4","8","-8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of a line perpendicular to the line 3x + 2y + 4 = 0 and passing through the point (5, 6)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3x + 2y - 27 = 0","2x - 3y + 8 = 0","x - 2y - 3 = 0","3x + 2y = -8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two perpendicular lines PQ and QR intercept at (1, -1). If the equation of PQ is: x - 2y + 2y + 4 = 0, find the equation of QR<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x - 2y + 1 = 0","2y + x - 3 = 0","x- 2y - 3 = 0","2x + y - 1 = 0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differentiate (2x+5)<sup>2<\/sup>(x-4) with respect to x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4(2x+5)(x-4)","4(2x+5)(4x-3)","(2x+5)(2x-13)","(2x+5)(6x-11)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the slope of the curve y= 2x<sup>2<\/sup>+5x-3 at (1,4)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","7","6","4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the probability that a number selected at random from 20 to 30 is a&nbsp; prime number or a multiple of 3<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6\/11","4\/11","2\/11","8\/11"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three numbers a, b and c are in the ratio 3:2:5. The value of 4a-c\/a + 2b is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2","2 1\/3","3\/7","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If u= {integers &lt; 20}, X= {multiples of 4}, Y={multiples of 3}, the element of XOY are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["{12}","{3,6,9,12,15,18}","{3,6,9,15,18}","{4,8,16,20}"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Points P and Q are respectively 24m north and 7m east of a point R. What is the bearing of Q from P to the nearest whole degree?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["286<sup>0<\/sup>","16<sup>0<\/sup>","73<sup>0<\/sup>","103<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Factorise 35-2b-b<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["(7 + b)(5-b)","(b+7)(b-5)","(7+b)(5+b)","(35-2b)(b-1)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 3log a + 5log a-6loga=log 64, what is&nbsp; a?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","8","16","6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What values of k make the expression x<sup>2<\/sup> - 8x + k = 0 a perfect square?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","8","16"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of a line with the gradient- 2 passing through the point (1, 2).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["y = 4 - 2x","y = 4 + 2x","y = 2x + 4","y = 2x - 2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The interior angles of a pentagon are 130\u00b0, 118\u00b0,78\u00b0, and x. Find the value of x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75\u00b0","108\u00b0","120\u00b0","214\u00b0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A chord&nbsp; is 5cm from the centre of a circle of diameter 26cm. Find the length of the chord<\/strong><\/p>","options":["35cm","30cm","24cm","14cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The locus of a point which is equidistant from two given fixed points is the _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Perpendicular bisector of the straight line joining them","Parallel line to the straight line joining them","Transverse to the straight line joining them","Angle bisector of 90\u00b0 which the straight line makes with the horizontal"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One-third of the children in a village were vaccinated against meningitis. If 680 of the children have been vaccinated, find the number of children in the village<\/strong><\/p>","options":["680","2040","1020","3800"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fair die is rolled once, find the probability of getting a number greater than 6<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/6","1","2\/3","0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A ball is drawn from a box containing 12 red balls, 8 white balls and 10 green balls. What is the probability of drawing a red, white or green ball?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/5","1\/3","1","0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x varies inversely as y and x = 2\/3 and y = 9, find the value of y when x = 3\/4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/9","1\/18","3\/9","8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The angle between latitude 30<sup>o<\/sup>S and 13<sup>o<\/sup>N is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["17<sup>o<\/sup>","33<sup>o<\/sup>","43<sup>o<\/sup>","53<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ratio a:b = 1\/2: 3\/4 and b:c = 1\/3: 5\/9. What is a:c?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1:2","2:5","3:7","3:4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three boys shared some quantity of apples. The first received 1\/4 of the apples, the second received 2\/3 of the remainder. The third boy received 12 apples which remained. How many apples did they share?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60","48","36","24"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a and b are the roots&nbsp; of the quadratic equation x<sup>2<\/sup>-10x+21=0 find the value of 1\/a<sup>2<\/sup>+1\/b<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["26\/441","58\/441","3\/441","30\/441"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contains three red and five white balls of equal sizes. Two balls are picked at random one after the other without replacement. What is the probability that both balls are of the same colour<\/strong><\/p>","options":["13\/32","3\/28","5\/14","13\/28"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two cards are picked at random from a pack of 52 playing cards, one at a time with replacement. What is the probability that the two cards are both spades and both hearts.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8\/169","1\/16","1\/8","1\/32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The numerator of a fraction is 5 less than the denominator. If 6 is added to the numerator and 4 to the denominator the fraction is doubled. What is the fraction ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/7","5\/8","3\/8","-1\/4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The total of four numbers is 1214<sub>five.&nbsp;<\/sub>What is their average, expressed in base five ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["303.10","242.4","541","114"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can a referee choose three footballers out of twelve footballers to represent a school competition<\/strong><\/p>","options":["220","1320","6","720"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The n<sup>th<\/sup> term of the sequence 2, 6, 18, 54.... is 4374. Find the number of n<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a class of 50 students, 30 speak Edo while 19 speak Yoruba and 7 students speak both language. How many students speak neither of the languages ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","8","7","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of digits of a two digit number is 13 and the units is 3 less than the tens digit. What is the number ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["47","74","58","85"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the universal set U = {x:x is a natural number and 1&lt;x&lt;9}, P = {x:1&lt;x&lt;4} and Q = (1,2,3,5,7). Find PUQ<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9)","(1,2,3,4,5,7)","(1,2,3,4)","(6,8,9)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sold a radio set to B at a prodit of 10% and B sold it for N2612.50 at a loss of 5%. The cost of the radio to A was?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N2375","N2750","N2500","N2488"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Without the use of table, evaluate&nbsp;log<sub>10<\/sub> &radic;35 +&nbsp;log<sub>10<\/sub> &radic;2 -&nbsp;log<sub>10<\/sub> &radic;7<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","2","5","1\/2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A number is selected at random from the numbers 1 to 30 inclusive. What is the probability that it is divisible by 2 and 5?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["19\/30","3\/5","3\/10","7\/10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Divide the octal number 106245 by the octal 137<\/strong><\/p>","options":["573","776","435","1118"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Insert two geometric means between 32 and 62<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>","options":["(16 <sup>48<\/sup>\/<Sub>125<\/sub>, 32)","(40, 50)","(44.72, 52.87)","(47.25, 54.88)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man took a loan of NP at the rate of 4% per annum simple interest. If at the end of 5 years he paid back N720, find the value of P?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N456","N500","N556","N600"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man left N5720 to be shared among his son and three daughters. Each daughter's share was 3\/4 of the son's share. How much did the son receive?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1320","N3960","N1430","N1760"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of eight boys whose masses are 56,62,58,65,50,49,57 and 59<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","26","0","5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sector on a pie chart representing the number of students offering mathematics has an angle of 24<sup>0<\/sup>. If 8 students offer mathematics, the total number of students in the class is?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["80","96","100","150"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean age of a class of twenty students is 12. If their teacher's age is included, the mean becomes 13. The age of the teacher is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["33","39","28","25"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the remainder when the polynomial f (x)= 2x<sup>2<\/sup>-5x-5 is divided by (2x+1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-7","-11\/2","-9\/2","-2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The common ratio of the exponential sequence (G.P) log x, log x<sup>2<\/sup>, log x<sup>4<\/sup>_______ is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["X","2","log x","log 2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the equation log<sub>2<\/sub> (x-1) + log(x+2)=2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x=0, or 1","x= 1 or 2","x=2 or -3","x= 1\/2 or 10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate, correct to one decimal place, the standard deviation of the numbers -1, 5, 0, 2, and 9<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7.2","6.6","3.6","3.2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The probability of an event P is 3\/4 while that of another event Q is 1\/6, if the probability of both P and Q is 1\/12. What is the probability of either P or Q<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/96","1\/6","5\/6","11\/12"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the compound interest on N2,000.00 for 2 years at 10% per annum<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N420.00","N400.00","N320.00","N200.00"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A box contains 40.1m<sup>3<\/sup> of air. If the box is of length 5.23m and breadth 2.34m, calculate its height<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5.35m","3.28m","0.31m","0.19"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A father is now twice as old as his son. Fourteen years ago he was four times as old as his son. How old are the son and father?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12 years, 24 years","21 years, 42 years","35 years, 70 years","23 years, 46 years"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>An open rectangular tank; 4m long, 3m wide and 4m high is made out of thin metal sheet. Find the area of the metal sheet used in its constrution<\/strong><\/p>","options":["80m<sup>2<\/sup>","64m<sup>2<\/sup>","68m<sup>2<\/sup>","76m<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The width of a rectangle is 6m shorter than the length. If the area of the rectangle is 216m<sup>2<\/sup>, find the perimeter of the rectangle<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30m","50m","60m","40m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Add the same number to the numerator and denominator of <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>18<\/sub>&nbsp;If the resulting fraction is <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;then the number added is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["13","14","15","12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A teacher contributes 7% of his income into a fund and his wife contributes 4% of her income. If the husband earns N5,500.00 per annum and his wife earns N4,000 per annum, find the sum of their annual contributions&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1,045","N605","N545","N490"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 5, x, y, 40 are in geometric progression, find x and y respectively<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2 and 10","20 and 10","10 and 20","10 and 2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>2\/5 of the student in a class offer further mathematics. If 14 students offer further mathematics, how many students are there in the class ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30","35","40","45"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man is five times as old as his son. If the sum of their ages is 72years, find the difference between their ages.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["18 years","40 years","38 years","48 years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>An arc of a circle of radius 6cm is 8cm long, find the area of the sector<\/strong><\/p>","options":["48cm<sup>2<\/sup>","36cm<sup>2<\/sup>","24cm<sup>2<\/sup>","<sup>51<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the length of a side of a square which is equal in area to a rectangle measuring 45cm by 5cm<\/strong><\/p>","options":["25cm","23cm","16cm","15cm"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Each side of a regular polygon subtends an angle of 30\u00b0 at its center. Calculate each interior angle.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75\u00b0","95\u00b0","150\u00b0","155\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>If two triangles are similar, which of the following is true ? Their<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Corresponding sides are equal","Corresponding angles are equal","Areas are equal","Perimeters"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x=924<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>-76<sup>2<\/sup>. Find the values of x in standard form<\/strong><\/p>","options":["848000","8.48 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>","2.48 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>","4.8 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Convert 111110<sub>2<\/sub> to base 10<\/strong><\/p>","options":["41","51","62","71"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 29th term of the sequence 3,8,13,18... is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["133","135","138","143"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x varies inversely as y and x = 2\/3 and y = 9, find the value of y when x = 3\/4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/9","1\/18","3\/9","8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is factor of rs + tr - pt - ps?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(p-s)","(s-p)","(r-p)","(r+p)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of three consecutive integers is 36. Find the value of the middle one<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","13","14","15"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>An important annoucement was brodcast from London at 4.40pm G.M.T and was picked up by a ship Navigator on longitude 35<sup>0<\/sup>W. What was the local time for the ship?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7.00pm","2.20pm","6.40pm","6.00pm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate x<sup>4<\/sup> - 3xy given that x= +2 and y= -5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","46","-139","111"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 13<sub>k<\/sub> = 12<sub>10<\/sub>. Find the value of k<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","5","7","9"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate 20% x 12.5%<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.025","0.0025","1.025","1.25"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the simple interest on N20,000.00 in 2 years at a rate of 13% per annum<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N5200.00","N5538.00","N113600.00","N146078.00"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The population of a village is 5846. Express this number to three signigicant figures<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5850","5846","585","584"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bank manager contributes 7% of his income into a fund and his wife contributes 4% of her income. The husband earns N556,000 per annum and the wife earns N100,000 per annum, find the sum of their annual contribution to the fund<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N60,500","N51,500","N42,920","N44,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>P, Q, R share N680 so that for every N1 that R gets, Q gets N2 and for every N1 that Q gets, P gets N4. How much does Q get<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N200","N220","N210","N320"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a TV set is sold for N18,700 the profit is 10%. What should be the selling prize to make a profit of 18%?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N17,060","N19,020","N20,000","N22,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a class of 35 students, 19 take history and 12 take economics. If 5 take both subjects, how many take neither?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","5","9"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A container 8cm high has a volume 60cm<sup>3<\/sup>. Find the volume of a similar container 40cm high<\/strong><\/p>","options":["300cm<sup>3<\/sup>","900cm<sup>3<\/sup>","1500cm<sup>3<\/sup>","7200cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many different committees of 4 can be selected from 10 people?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["610","210","151200","25"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the probability of selecting a figure which is a parallelogram from a square, a rectagle, a rhombus, a kite and a trapezium<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/5","2\/5","4\/5","1\/5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify 2 + 4 <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>8<\/sub> x 1&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> - <sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub> + 4&nbsp;<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10 215\/352","5 233\/416","4 103\/416","2 1\/123"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 122<sub>y<\/sub> = 17<sub>10<\/sub>, find the value of y<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","3","2","1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the following equation (0.25)<sup>x+1<\/sup> = 16<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","1","-3","-1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>At what rate will N9360 yield a simple interest of N75.50 in 9months? Express your answers in 2 significant figures<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.08","3.2","2.1","1.6"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>ATB bank had shares to sell to the general public of 50 kobo at N5.50 per share. A man invested a total of N132,660. How many shares did he buy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["24120","13220","101210","9140"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the roots of x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x + k = 0 are n and n-1, find the value of the constant k<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7","6","-3","-6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Factorise x<sup>3<\/sup> - 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x + 6<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x+1)(x+2)(x+3)","(x-1)(x-2)(x-3)","(x-1)(x-2)(x+3)","(x-1)(x+2)(x-3)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cup of beans costs p kobo. How many cups can be bought with q naira<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100q\/p","q\/p","p\/q","p\/100q"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of five numbers is 6 and mean deviation is 4. Find the fifth number if mean deviation of the first four numbers is 3.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["26","14","12","8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The number of goals scored by a school team in 10 handball matches is as follows: 3,5,7,7,8,8,8,11,11,12. Find the probability that in a match the school will score at most 8 goals<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7\/10","3\/10","2\/8","1\/10"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area of the curved surface of a cone whose base radius is 6cm and whose height is 8cm.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["188.5cm<sup>2<\/sup>","1320cm<sup>2<\/sup>","188cm<sup>2<\/sup>","188.08<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>An isosceles triangle of sides 13, 13 and 10cm is inscribed in a circle. What is the radius of the circle?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15.04 cm","7.0 4cm","8.04 cm","6.04 cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the equation for all the positive values of 13<sup>0<\/sup> lens thru 360<sup>0<\/sup>, 3tan 111.2 = -1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["135<sup>0<\/sup> or 315<sup>0<\/sup>","45<sup>0<\/sup> or 135<sup>0<\/sup>","315<sup>0<\/sup> or 45<sup>0<\/sup>","315<sup>0<\/sup> or 180<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>18 labourers dig a ditch 80m long in 5 days. How long will it take 24 labourers to dig a ditch 64m long?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8 days","5 days","3 days","2 days"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A simple interest on a loan of N1000 is increased from 5% to 5 1\/2%. What would be the interest for a period of 3 months?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N13.75","N11.50","N8.75","N2.25"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>What must be subtracted from x<sup>3<\/sup> + 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 3x + 5 to make it exactly divisible by (x-2)?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["17","15","12","9"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is different from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Binomial distribution","Frequency distribution","Normal distribution","Poisson distribution"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Lines of latitude indicate distances from&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the poles","the equator","greenwich","anywhere"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of three numbers in base two is 1101. If the first two numbers are 1011 and 1101 find the third number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["- 11<sub>2<\/sub>","- 101<sub>2<\/sub>","- 1011<sub>2<\/sub>","- 1111<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A businessman decided to give 10% discount on all the purchases from his store. How much would a customer pay for a shirt originally marked N540 ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N594.00","N550.00","N530.00","N486.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the equation 3<sup>x<\/sup>=1\/81<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","3","-4","-3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express y in terms of x if (1\/2)<sup>log2<\/sup><\/strong><strong><sup>(y+3)<\/sup>=2<sup>x<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["y=2<sup>x<\/sup> - 3","y=2<sup>4x<\/sup> - 3","y=2<sup>4x<\/sup> -9","y=2<sup>x<\/sup> + 9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Without using tables, simplify log<sub>9<\/sub>3<\/strong><sup>&nbsp;<\/sup><strong>+ log<sub>9<\/sub>243&nbsp;<\/strong>- <strong>2log<sub>9<\/sub>3<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","2","1","0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that p(x) = 2x<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><strong>+5x<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong>-<strong>9x-18, find the value of p(-1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","5","-2","-5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that Q(X) = ax<sup>2<\/sup>+bx+1 and Q(1) = 6 and Q(-1) = 2, determine the value of a and b<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a=5;b=3","a=3,b=2","a=-3,b=-2","a=-5;b=3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>P varies directly with R and inversely with the square of Q. P = 12 when R=18 and Q=2. Find the constant, K of the variation.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4\/3","8\/3","3\/4","3\/8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the first twenty terms of the linear sequences 5,9,13,17 _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1000","960","880","860"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The third term of a geometric progression (G.P) is 63 and the fifth term is 567. Find the sum of the first six terms of the progression.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2548","2448","2348","2248"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the inequality m\/3 +1\/4 &gt; 3m\/8<\/strong><\/p>","options":["m > - 6","m > 6","m < -6","m < 6"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The angle of depression of a boat at sea from the top of a cliff is 82<sup>0<\/sup><\/strong><strong>. What is the angle of elevation of the top of the cliff from the boat?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["98<sup>0<\/sup>","90<sup>0<\/sup>","88<sup>0<\/sup>","82<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The interior angle of a regular polygon in thrice the exterior angle. How many sides has the polygon.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differentiate with respect to x the function y=(2x+4)(3x-1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3x+10","12x","12x+5","12x+10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if x<\/strong><strong>y-5x=3<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5-2xy\/x<sup>2<\/sup>","(5-y)\/x","5+2xy\/x","5-3xy\/x"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differentiate with respect to x, y=sin (2x-4)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4Cos(2x-4)","3Cos(2x-4)","2Cos(2x-4)","2Cos(2x+4)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three angles of a nonagon are equal and the sum of six other angles is 1110\u00b0. Calculate the size of one of the equal angles<\/strong><\/p>","options":["210\u00b0","150\u00b0","105\u00b0","50\u00b0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>For two values of y which satisfy the simultaneous equation x + y = 5, x<sup>2<\/sup> - 2y<sup>2<\/sup> = 1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12, -2","-12, 12","-12, 2","2, -2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The minimum value of y in the equation y=x<sup>2<\/sup>-6x+8 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8","3","0","-1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the first 21 terms of the progression -10, -8, -6___<\/strong><\/p>","options":["180","190","200","210"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the eleventh term of the progression, 4,8,16______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2<sup>13<\/sup>","2<sup>12<\/sup>","2<sup>11<\/sup>","2<sup>10<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Convert 241 in base 5 to base 8<\/strong><\/p>","options":["71<sub>8<\/sub>","107<sub>8<\/sub>","76<sub>8<\/sub>","241<sub>8<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"}]